天啊
Oh man.
哇哦
Wow.
我打小之后就再没回来过
I haven't been here since I was a little kid.
我还以为你在这长大的
I thought you grew up here.
就前面拐角那一带
Like round the corner.
我就是在那个台阶上把牙磕掉的
I knocked my tooth out on that step.
脑子都磕坏了
Got me brain damaged.
虽然比不上纽约 但这是咱俩的小窝
It's not New York, but... it's ours.
我觉得以后会很快活 对吧?
I think it's gonna be pretty sick, no?
嗯?
Yeah?
- 我把架子鼓运过来成不?- 想都别想
- I could send for my drum kit? - No way.
不行?
No?
我叔叔以前爱囤东西 我没想到这儿...
My uncle was a hoarder. I didn't realise how much...
原来这么宽敞
space there was in here.
挺清净啊
It's peaceful.
在这地方录专辑再舒服不过了
I can just record an album out here so easily.
- 格蕾丝 - 干嘛?
- Gracie! - What?
我找到个书房
I found an office!
哦
Oh.
你以后可以在这写你那部伟大的美国小说了
You can write your Great American Novel up here.
哇
Whoa!
怎么了?
What?
呃...
Um...
没事就几只老鼠
It's alright. It's just a little rat situation.
咱们该养只猫了
We should get a cat.
你可以从早写到晚 安静得只剩鸟叫
You can write all day, every day. Nothing but the birds singing.
他怎么死的?
How did he die?
呃...
Um...
我不知道
I don't know.
就这了
Here we are.
得先找把扫帚
We need a broom.
嘿嘿嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
嘿
Hey.
来吧 我们再扭一曲
Came on, let's twist again
嘿 你妈妈呢?
Hey! Where's your mommy?
小南瓜 你妈呢?
Pumpkin, where's your mommy?
哦 糟咯
Oh, no!
妈妈去哪了?
Where's Mommy?
天啊
Oh, God.
格蕾丝
Grace.
我妈想顺道过来一趟
Mom wanted to stop by.
哦?
Oh?
我跟她说了没大 就只是咱俩自己的事
I told her it wasn't a big deal. It's like a "us" thing.
反正也就待六个月吧 所以...
And it's just for six months, anyway, so...
嗯
Mm- hmm.
我就是有点过意不去
I just feel kind of bad,
我觉得她只是想有人陪
'cause I think she just wants the company.
我不介意她来
I don't mind her coming.
真怪她好像不知道一个人怎么过了
It's weird. It's like she doesn't know how to function any more.
做饭还按两人份 她跟你说过吗?
She's still cooking for two people. Did she tell you that?
太甜了
It's too sweet.
是吗?我觉得挺好啊
Yeah? No, it's nice.
他喜欢甜的
He liked it.
真正当妈的会烤个蛋糕
A real mom would have baked a cake.
再来一瓶?
Want another one?
怎么他妈的这么热?
Why is it so fuckin' hot?
“怎么他妈的这么热?”
"Why is it so fuckin' hot?"
这里一直这么热
It's always hot.
孩子睡了
Boy's asleep.
嗯
Mm- hmm.
你要看吗?
You wanna look?
格蕾丝 你怎么能对星星这么无动于衷?
How can you not give a shit about the stars, Grace?
看着它们 我觉得自己啥也不是
Well, they make me feel like nothing.
我倒喜欢这种成为浩瀚宇宙一份子的感觉
I like they make me feel like I'm part of something bigger.
你就喜欢觉得自己啥也不是?
You like to feel like nothing?
不
No.
你知道外面有多少个宇宙吗?
You know how many universes there are out there?
在别的宇宙里我们在干嘛 还会在一起吗?
What are we doing in the different universe? Are we together?
当然
Sure we are.
那我是不是搖滾女明星?
Am I a rock star?
嗯...
Hmm...
在别的宇宙里你会唱歌吗?
Can you sing in a different universe?
嘿
Hey.
会 我敢肯定你是
Yeah, I'm sure you're a rock star.
那我们会不会做爱?
Do we fuck?
会
Uh- huh.
一直做?
All the time?
你说啥?
Hey, what?
我们 到底 会不会做爱?
Do. We. Fuck?
跟兔子一样频繁
Like rabbits.
你听见孩子声音了吗?
Do you hear him?
没听见
No.
他在哭呢 你听
He's crying. Listen.
格蕾丝 这儿一点声音都没有
Grace, it's totally silent.
我把你说烦了?
Am I boring you?
跟你无关 宇宙的问题
Not you. The universe.
谁在乎啊?
Who gives a shit?
摸起来像女孩吗?
Does it feel like a girl?
女孩摸起来什么感觉?
What does a girl feel like?
要是右边动得多点
If it moves more on the right,
那你多半怀的是男孩
then you're probably having a boy.
你不想提前知道吗?
You didn't wanna know?
不想
Mm- mm.
格蕾丝 我...
Grace, I...
我当年也没提前去查自己怀的是啥
I didn't find out what I was having either.
我觉得那样挺好的
I think that's nice.
你不去查是因为你想要个女儿
You didn't find out 'cause you wanted a girl.
天啊 他又忘了喝
Oh, gosh. He forgets to drink.
哈利 你得喝一杯
Harry, you gotta have a drink.
不 我没有 我只是想要个孩子 谁在肚子里我都要
No, I didn't, I wanted a baby. I wanted whoever was in there.
是吗 然后你生下了杰克森?
Yeah? And you got Jackson?
真不走运
Unlucky.
我听到了 珍姨
I heard that, Auntie Jen.
格蕾丝 没胃口吗?
Are you off your food, Grace?
- 别管她 - 你刚才都没吃东西
- Leave her alone. - You didn't eat.
怀孕会让胃口变小
Being pregnant makes your stomach shrink.
那是胡扯
That's bullshit.
那小家伙每天每分钟都在吸你的营养
It's sucking on you every minute of the day.
然后你就会饿坏 我那时候怎么吃都吃不够
Then you'll be famished. I couldn't get enough in me.
你这毛病一直没改 是吧?
That never went away, did it?
你倒会说 你自己又有什么借口?
You can talk. What's your excuse?
自己从没生过 吃起来像刚生了三胞胎似的
Never had a baby but always ate as though you'd just had triplets.
你知道吗 格蕾丝 要是你生的是个爱哭鬼...
You know, Grace, if you get a screamer...
她不会生爱哭鬼的
She's not gonna get a screamer.
杰克森小时候就是个爱哭鬼
Jackson was a screamer.
- 胡说 - 杰克森小时候可乖了
- That's a lie! - Jackson was a sweetheart.
重点是 真遇上那种 就让孩子自己哭去
The point is, if you do, let the baby cry.
你就暂时离开一下 别把自己弄得又累又紧绷
Just walk away from it. Don't let yourself get tired, stressed.
这么说太吓人了
That's a horrible thing to say.
简直是慢性折磨
Slow fuckin' death.
你要是状态不好 对谁都不好 尤其是对孩子
If you're not at your best, it's no good for anyone, especially the baby.
而且孩子哭不代表他难受
And a crying baby doesn't mean it's in pain.
那是他们唯一和大人的交流方式
It's the only way they have of communicating.
不 才不是这样
No, it's not.
人家爱说那种屁话 是因为想着能心安理得丢下孩子
People say that shit because they wanna walk away from their kid.
反正我整天就只是在照顾哈利
Anyway, all I do is take care of Harry.
- 勉强算吧 - 要是你需要我的话...
- Barely. - If you need me...
- 她不用 - 我们走几步就到
- She doesn't. - ...we're just a walk away.
爸 你在这干嘛 想看灰熊队比赛吗?
What you doing in here, Pop? Wanna watch the Grizzlies?
想拆礼物吗?儿
Wanna open some of those presents?
谁的礼物?
Whose presents?
给宝宝的
For the baby.
不用 我得把这几双鞋先理清楚
No, I gotta sort out these shoes.
- 好吧 - 这双鞋拿错了
- Okay. - They're the wrong ones.
我看着挺好
They look good to me.
- 妈你吃饱了吗?- 宝贝 我吃撑了
- You had enough to eat, Mom? - Honey, I'm stuffed.
帮你爸倒点喝的好吗?
Would you get your dad something to drink, please?
给 老爸
Here you go, Pop.
别再给我吃派了
No more pie.
唉 我也是吃撑了
Well, I'm stuffed.
就是停不下嘴 每逢过节都这样
Can't stop eating. It's the same every holiday.
你能吃 你一直都很瘦
Well, you can do it. You've always been skinny.
格蕾丝就喜欢我瘦点 对吧 宝贝?
Grace likes me lean. Don't you, baby?
你可以一月份再饿回来
You can starve in January.
你们都在干嘛 你们怎么在这儿?
What are y'all doing? Why are y'all here?
这是弗兰克的房子
This is Frank's house.
这是他的房子
It's his house.
哈利 这里现在是格蕾丝和杰克森的...
Harry, this is Grace and Jackson's- -
不 这是我弟的房子
No, this is my brother's house.
亲爱的弗兰克已经不在了
Sweetheart, Frank's not here.
都给我滚出我弟的房子
Get out of my brother's house!
杰克森
Jackson.
哈利
Harry.
Harry!
找到合脚的那双了吗?
Did you find the right size?
你好
Hello.
是宝宝吗?
Is it a baby?
- 是宝宝 - 是男孩吗?
- A baby. - A boy?
我不知道 也许吧
I don't know. I think, maybe.
是男孩
It is.
哦
Oh?
别让他一个人哭着
Don't leave him to cry.
我不会
I won't.
你知道吗 他来的时候会先像只猫
You know, when he comes, he's a cat.
又像熊 又像宝宝
He's a bear and a baby.
他也是你 是你们所有人
And he's you, he's all of you.
他会很有趣的
He's gonna be so funny.
嗨 找到想要的东西了吗?
Hi. Find everything you're looking for?
你是说人生吗?
In life?
车要加油吗?
Any gas for your car?
- 不用 - 行
- No. - Alrighty.
我超爱这玩意 不管里面加了什么 简直像魔法
I love this stuff. Whatever they put in that powder, it's like magic.
你要再拿一袋的话 两袋一起六美元
It's two for six dollars if you want another.
不用了
I'm good.
这一袋四美元 另一袋两美元
This one's four.And the other one is two.
我知道了 不用了 谢了
I get it.No, thanks.
是个男孩 对吧?
He's a boy, right?
他好可爱 嗨 小帅哥
He's so cute. Hi there, handsome.
嗨 小甜心
Hi there, sweetie- pie.
- 他有名字吗?- 没有
- Does he have a name? - No.
我们决定先不给他起名
We decided not to name him.
哦
Oh.
宝贝你几个月了?等等 让我猜猜
How old are you, sweetie? Wait. Let me guess.
我特别擅长这个 大概六个月?
I'm really good at this. About six months?
你为什么要一直说话?
Why are you talking?
你说话之前有想过自己要说什么 或者为什么要开口吗?
Do you ever think about what you'll say or why you're speaking?
还是一张嘴就叭叭说个不停?
Or do you just open your mouth and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah?
再过差不多三十秒我就走了 我们没必要聊天
In about 30 seconds, I'll be gone. We don't need to speak.
好
Okay.
每当你靠近一点 我就再多露一点真心
...every time you move I let a little more show
你可以好好利用我 所以别拒绝我 米基
There's something you can use So don't say no, Mickey
来吧 给我你能给的一切
So, come on and give it to me Anyway you can
不管你怎么玩 我都照单全收
Anyway you wanna do it I'll take it like a man
但求你 宝贝 别把我一个人晾在这潮湿里 米基
But please, baby, please Don't leave me in the damp, Mickey
噢 米基 真可惜你还是不懂
Oh, Mickey, what a pity You don't understand
你牵着我手时也抓住了我的心
You take me by the heart When you take me by the hand
噢 米基 你这么迷人 难道你就不明白吗?
Oh, Mickey, you're so pretty Can't you understand?
就是你这样的家伙 米基
It's guys like you, Mickey
噢 你对我做的一切 米基米基
Oh, what you do, Mickey, do, Mickey